"use strict";(self.webpackChunklearning=self.webpackChunklearning||[]).push([[6592],{6592:(e,n,a)=>{a.r(n),a.d(n,{gramma:()=>t});a(5043);const t=[{semester:1,grade:8,questions:[{id:41,extra:"",question:"John has been ___ a real effort to achieve good results in his final exam.\n                ",options:["doing","bringing","making","boiling"],answer:"3",rewrite:"",explanation:"make an effort to V: n\u1ed7 l\u1ef1c \u0111\u1ec3 l\xe0m g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"My daughter spends 2 hours a day ___ her homework.\n                ",options:["seeing","giving","acting","doing"],answer:"4",rewrite:"",explanation:"do the homework/ housework: l\xe0m b\xe0i t\u1eadp v\u1ec1 nh\xe0/ vi\u1ec7c nh\xe0 "},{id:41,extra:"",question:"If you _____ your best, you are likely to pass the exam.\n                ",options:["go","do","get","give"],answer:"2",rewrite:"",explanation:"do your best: c\u1ed1 h\u1ebft m\xecnh"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"She wanted to ___ a look at the picture I painted yesterday.\n                ",options:["make","set","have","own"],answer:"3",rewrite:"",explanation:"have a look at somebody/something: nh\xecn xem c\xe0i g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"We ____ a great time with each other during the school trip.\n                ",options:["had","made","saw","acted"],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:"have a great time: c\xf3 m\u1ed9t kho\u1ea3ng th\u1eddi gian tuy\u1ec7t v\u1eddi"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Joey was responsible for ____ arrangements for our business trip.\n                ",options:["going","making","leading","getting"],answer:"2",rewrite:"",explanation:"make arrangements: s\u1eafp x\u1ebfp"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"He asked the students to ____ the exercise 3B on page 14.\n                ",options:["have","do","bring","call"],answer:"2",rewrite:"",explanation:"do exercises: l\u1ea3m b\xe0i t\u1eadp, t\u1eadp th\u1ec3 d\u1ee5c"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Martin is reserved by nature, so he finds it very hard to ____ friends at his new school.\n                ",options:["make","go","fall","give"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",explanation:"make friends: k\u1ebft b\u1ea1n"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"One of my uncles ___ an accident last night. Fortunately, he just suffered minor injuries.\n                ",options:["took","asked","tried","had"],answer:"4",rewrite:"",explanation:"have an accident: b\u1ecb tai n\u1ea1n"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"We wil ___ a small party once we move to a bigger house.\n                ",options:["gain","sell","have","catch"],answer:"3",rewrite:"",explanation:"have a party: t\u1ed5 ch\u1ee9c b\u1eefa ti\u1ec7c"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Many students have difficulty in ____ informed career choices.\n                ",options:["leading","seeing","calling","making"],answer:"4",rewrite:"",explanation:"make choices: \u0111\u01b0a ra l\u1ef1a ch\u1ecdn"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"My father finally ___ a decision to rent this car.\n                ",options:["made","acted","caught","went"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",explanation:"make a decision: \u0111\u01b0a ra quy\u1ebft \u0111\u1ecbnh"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"It's very difficult to ____ accurate predictions about the weather.\n                ",options:["send","make","bring","create"],answer:"2",rewrite:"",explanation:"make a prediction: \u0111\u01b0a ra d\u1ef1 \u0111o\xe1n"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Drinking soft drinks before an exam can ___ harm to your health.\n                ",options:["take","ask","do","go"],answer:"3",rewrite:"",explanation:"do harm somebody/something: g\xe2y h\u1ea1i cho ai \u0111\xf3/ g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"You should ___ a break if you feed a bit tired.\n                ",options:["have","make","sell","throw"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",explanation:"have a break: ngh\u0129 gi\u1ea3i lao"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"The student ____ difficulty in understanding what the teacher said.\n                ",options:["found","had","set","did"],answer:"2",rewrite:"",explanation:"have difficulty in V_ing: g\u1eb7p kh\xf3 kh\u0103n trong vi\u1ec7c g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"The keynote speaker asked the audience to ____ some comment comments on his talk.\n                ",options:["do","see","try","make"],answer:"4",rewrite:"",explanation:"make a comment: \u0111\u01b0a ra b\xecnh lu\u1eadn"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Holland has been ___ progress in English since he changed his study method.\n                ",options:["tracing","coping","making","paying"],answer:"3",rewrite:"",explanation:"make progress: c\xf3 ti\u1ebfn b\u1ed9"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Susan ___ me a good turn when she agreed to look after my son.\n                ",options:["did","took","had","made"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",explanation:"do somebody a good turn: gi\xfap \u0111\u1ee1 ai"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Could you wait a few minutes? I'm _____ my hair.\n                ",options:["calling","going","taking","doing"],answer:"4",rewrite:"",explanation:"do your hair: l\xe0m t\xf3c"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Michael is a trustworthy man, so it's a good idea to ____ business with him.\n                ",options:["make","lay","do","get"],answer:"3",rewrite:"",explanation:"do business with somebody: l\xe0m kinh doanh v\u1edbi ai"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"They ______  a big row last night about where to go this summer holiday.\n                ",options:["took","called","had","went"],answer:"3",rewrite:"",explanation:"have a big row: c\u1ea3i nhau to"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Try not _____ any spelling mistakes in the writing test.\n                ",options:["make","go","bring","set"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",explanation:"make a mistake: ph\u1ea1m l\u1ed7i"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"As usual, he started to ___ an excuse for his being late.\n                ",options:["see","make","go","act"],answer:"2",rewrite:"",explanation:"make an excuse: b\xe0o ch\u1eefa, \u0111\u01b0a ra l\xfd do"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Mary ___ the shopping with her friends at a mall yesterday morning.\n                ",options:["went","did","had","phoned"],answer:"2",rewrite:"",explanation:"do the shopping = go shopping: \u0111i mua s\u1eafm"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"The scholar ______ a major contribution to a cure for coronavirus.\n                ",options:["held","went","played","made"],answer:"4",rewrite:"",explanation:"made a contribution: c\xf3 \u0111\xf3n g\xf3p"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"I ___ a long chat with Peter about his future plan last week.\n                ",options:["had","set","pointed","went"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",explanation:"have a chat: c\xf3 m\u1ed9t cu\u1ed9c tr\xf2 chuy\u1ec7n"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Could you ___ me a favour and pick up my kids?\n                ",options:["sell","play","catch","do"],answer:"4",rewrite:"",explanation:"do somebody a favour: gi\xfap \u0111\u1ee1 ai"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"They _____ some slight improvements to the well of the house.\n                ",options:["gave","went","made","played"],answer:"3",rewrite:"",explanation:"make improvaments: th\u1ef1c hi\u1ec7n c\u1ea3i ti\u1ebfn"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"One of my friends ___ an argument with the policeman.\n                ",options:["had","caught","shined","asked"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",explanation:"have an argument with somebody: c\xe3i nhau v\u1edbi ai"}]},{semester:1,grade:8,questions:[{id:41,extra:"",question:"\n                ",options:["","","",""],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:""},{id:41,extra:"",question:"\n                ",options:["","","",""],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:""},{id:41,extra:"",question:"\n                ",options:["","","",""],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:""},{id:41,extra:"",question:"\n                ",options:["","","",""],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:""},{id:41,extra:"",question:"\n                ",options:["","","",""],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:""},{id:41,extra:"",question:"\n                ",options:["","","",""],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:""},{id:41,extra:"",question:"\n                ",options:["","","",""],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:""},{id:41,extra:"",question:"\n                ",options:["","","",""],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:""},{id:41,extra:"",question:"\n                ",options:["","","",""],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:""},{id:41,extra:"",question:"\n                ",options:["","","",""],answer:"",rewrite:"",explanation:""}]}]}}]);
//# sourceMappingURL=6592.9f8bbb32.chunk.js.map